livechart.me 2019-04-07

# Privacy Policy | LiveChart.me

LAST REVISED ON: **October 10, 2016**

This Privacy Policy ( **“Policy”** ) describes how your personal information is collected, used, and disclosed by **LiveChart.me** and its related companies ( **“LiveChart”** or **“LiveChart.me”** or **“We”** or **“Us”** ). This Policy applies to the LiveChart.me websites available at livechart.me or any of our other websites that post this Policy (the **“Site”** ), LiveChart.me’s mobile applications ( **“Apps”** ), and our online services (the **“Services”** ). This Policy does not apply to websites or mobile applications that post different statements.

#### WHAT WE COLLECT

We collect information about you in a range of ways.

##### Information You Give Us

We collect any personal information you provide to us. For example, you may provide us your name, email address, date of birth, username, demographic information (such as your gender and occupation), precise location-based data and venue preferences, or other information you directly give us on the Services.

##### Information Automatically Collected

We automatically log information about you and your computer. For example, when visiting our Site, we log your computer operating system type,‎ browser type,‎ browser language,‎ the website you visited before browsing to our Site,‎ pages you viewed,‎ how long you spent on a page,‎ access times,‎ Internet protocol (IP) address and information about your use of and actions on our Site.

  * **Cookies**

We may log information using “cookies.” Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive by a website. Cookies help us make our Site and your visit better. We use cookies to see which parts of our Site people use and like, to allow you to customize your experience and to count visits to our Site. If you prefer, you can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies via your browser settings. Like most websites, if you turn your cookies off, some of our services may not function properly.

  * **Analytics**

We use analytics services such as (and not limited to) Google Analytics and Firebase Analytics to help analyze how users use the Site and Apps. These analytics uses cookies and other technological methods to collect and store information such as how often users visit the Site and Apps, what pages they visit, what features they use, and what other sites they used prior to coming to the Site. We use the information we get from analytics services only to improve our Site, our Apps, and our Services.

More information about Google Analytics: <http://www.google.com/privacy.html>, <http://www.google.com/analytics/tos.html>

Firebase Privacy Policy: <https://www.firebase.com/terms/privacy-policy.html>

  * **Advertising**

Our Services may contain sponsored links and adverts. These will typically be served through our advertising partners, to whom may have detailed privacy policies relating directly to the adverts they serve.

Clicking on any such adverts will send you to the advertisers website through a referral program which may use cookies and will track the number of referrals sent from our Services. This may include the use of cookies which may in turn be saved on your computers hard drive. Users should therefore note they click on sponsored external links at their own risk and LiveChart.me and its owners cannot be held liable for any damages or implications caused by visiting any external links mentioned. Please see the following links for more information about Google AdSense: <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html> and <http://www.google.com/privacy.html>.

    * Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on your prior visits to the Site.

    * Google's use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to you based on your visit to our Services and/or other sites on the Internet.

    * You may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting [Ads Settings](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/), or opt out of third-party vendor's use of cookies for interest based advertising by visiting [aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).

#### USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

We use personal information collected through our Services, or disclosed by you on our Site or in connection with our Services, for the purposes described in this Policy. For example, we may use your information to:

  * We use your personal information to operate, maintain, and improve our sites, products, and services.
  * We use your personal information to process and deliver contest entries and rewards.
  * We use your personal information to respond to comments and questions and provide customer service.
  * We use your personal information to communicate about promotions, upcoming events, and other news about products and services offered by us and our selected partners.
  * We use your personal information to protect, investigate, and deter against fraudulent, unauthorized, or illegal activity.

#### SHARING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

We do not share your personal information other than as follows:

  * With third party vendors, consultants and other service providers who work for us and need access to your information to do that work;
  * At your request, in the event that you opt-in to receive a service or a product from a third party;
  * As required or permitted by law;
  * To protect the rights and property of LiveChart.me, our agents, users, and others including to enforce our agreements, policies, and terms of use;
  * In an emergency to protect the personal safety of its users or any person;
  * In connection with or during negotiation of any merger, financing, acquisition, bankruptcy, dissolution, transaction or proceeding involving sale, transfer, divestiture or disclosure of all or a portion of our business or assets to another company.

#### ERASURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

In the event that you wish to remove personal information that you have provided to Us by creating an account, you can request the deletion your account through the account settings page. Upon requesting that your account be deleted, your account will be immediately deactivated and you will be allotted a seven (7) day grace period during which you may request that your account be reactivated. Because of the backup mechanisms We utilize, your account will be retained in an encrypted archive format for an additional fourteen (14) days after deletion.

#### SECURITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

We use reasonable efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of your personally identifiable information. Unfortunately, it is impossible to guarantee the security of data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network. Therefore, although we take reasonable measures to protect your information, we cannot ensure the security of any information you transmit to us and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your information, we will use reasonable efforts to ensure its security on our systems. We may provide links to third parties’ websites, which we do not control. We are not responsible for information that you provide to those third-party sites. We recommend that you review the privacy policies if any provided at those sites.

#### CONTACT INFORMATION

We welcome your comments or questions about this Privacy Policy. If you have any queries in regards to your privacy, our contact information is available on our contact page.

#### CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

We may change this Policy from time to time. If we make any changes to this Policy, we will change the Last Revised date above.
